<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.prof18.feedflow</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
  <name>FeedFlow</name>
  <summary>An open source, minimal RSS reader for your desktop</summary>
  <description>
    <p>FeedFlow is an open source RSS reader built for desktop — a fast, minimal timeline for your news, blogs, and feeds. No algorithms, no clutter, no noise.</p>

    <p>A Desktop-First Reading Experience</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Three-pane layout: sidebar, feed list, and article view — all visible at once</li>
      <li>Switch to single-pane mode if you prefer a focused view</li>
      <li>Keyboard shortcuts for everything — refresh with F5, navigate with arrow keys, mark as read with Ctrl+Shift+A</li>
      <li>The app remembers your window position and size between sessions</li>
      <li>Dark mode, light mode, and OLED black theme</li>
    </ul>

    <p>Read Articles Your Way</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Open articles in your default browser, or use Reader Mode for a distraction-free reading experience</li>
      <li>Adjust text size and spacing in Reader Mode for comfortable reading on any screen</li>
      <li>Prefetch and cache full article content for offline reading</li>
    </ul>

    <p>Sync Feeds Across All Your Devices</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Keep everything local, or sync with multiple backends</li>
      <li>Cloud storage sync with Dropbox</li>
      <li>Self-hosted and server sync with FreshRSS, Miniflux, Feedbin, or BazQux</li>
      <li>Your feeds, read status, and bookmarks stay in sync across Linux, Windows, Android, iOS, and macOS</li>
    </ul>

    <p>Stay Organized</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Import and export feeds with OPML — migrate from any RSS tool</li>
      <li>Block keywords to filter out unwanted content</li>
      <li>Organize feeds into categories and bookmark articles for later</li>
      <li>Search across all your feeds to find articles quickly</li>
    </ul>

    <p>Built for RSS, Atom, and the Open Web</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Supports RSS 2.0, RSS 1.0, and Atom feed formats</li>
      <li>Add feeds by URL or browse curated suggestions</li>
      <li>No account required to get started</li>
    </ul>

    <p>Open source with an active community. Available on all major platforms. Translated into 25+ languages.</p>
  </description>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.prof18.feedflow.desktop</launchable>
  
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Browse, select, and read in a fast three-pane layout</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/prof18/feed-flow/refs/heads/main/assets/linux-screenshots/1.home.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Read long articles in a clean distraction-free Reader Mode</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/prof18/feed-flow/refs/heads/main/assets/linux-screenshots/2.reader.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Choose local-only storage or sync with services that fit your workflow</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/prof18/feed-flow/refs/heads/main/assets/linux-screenshots/3.sync.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Adjust layout, density, and what details stay visible</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/prof18/feed-flow/refs/heads/main/assets/linux-screenshots/4.list.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/prof18/feed-flow/issues</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://feedflow.dev/</url>
  <url type="donation">https://www.paypal.me/MarcoGomiero</url>
  <url type="translate">https://hosted.weblate.org/projects/feedflow/</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://github.com/prof18/feed-flow</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/prof18/feed-flow</url>
  
  <developer id="com.prof18">
    <name>Marco Gomiero</name>
  </developer>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.0">
    <content_attribute id="social-info">mild</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>

  <releases>
      <release version="1.13.0" date="2026-04-27">
          <description>
              <p>Fixed a crash in the adaptive layout toolbar</p>
              <p>Search state now resets correctly when exiting search</p>
              <p>Bug fixing and improvements</p>
          </description>
      </release>

      <release version="1.12.0" date="2026-04-18">
          <description>
              <p>Refreshed reader mode with new floating toolbar and navigation bar</p>
              <p>Move to the next feed source with one click</p>
              <p>Delete all feeds in a category directly from the app</p>
              <p>Customize the feed list: hide unread dot, hide feed source, limit description lines</p>
              <p>Cleaner settings screen and refined scroll bars</p>
              <p>URL tooltip when hovering links</p>
              <p>Brand new app icon</p>
              <p>Better handling of invalid OPML and CSV imports</p>
              <p>Various stability and reliability improvements</p>
          </description>
      </release>

      <release version="1.11.2" date="2026-03-22">
          <description>
              <p>Added a new three-pane desktop layout and a switch for users who prefer the single-pane view.</p>
              <p>Added a dedicated Settings window with sections for reading, feed list, accounts, sync storage, and about.</p>
              <p>Moved accounts, add feed, edit feed, import and export, and blocked words into separate desktop windows.</p>
              <p>Improved the docked sidebar with clearer icons, better contrast, stronger selection states, and refreshed colors.</p>
              <p>Improved Reader Mode with a new engine, cleaner navigation buttons, better spacing, and a clearer split between list and article panes.</p>
              <p>Improved desktop context menus and scrollbars.</p>
              <p>Expanded Feed Suggestions with a new Marketing category and more curated sources.</p>
              <p>Fixed Reader Mode so fast article switches no longer show stale content.</p>
          </description>
      </release>

      <release version="1.11.1" date="2026-03-15">
          <description>
              <p>Added a new three-pane desktop layout and a switch for users who prefer the single-pane view.</p>
              <p>Added a dedicated Settings window with sections for reading, feed list, accounts, sync storage, and about.</p>
              <p>Moved accounts, add feed, edit feed, import and export, and blocked words into separate desktop windows.</p>
              <p>Improved the docked sidebar with clearer icons, better contrast, stronger selection states, and refreshed colors.</p>
              <p>Improved Reader Mode with a new engine, cleaner navigation buttons, better spacing, and a clearer split between list and article panes.</p>
              <p>Improved desktop context menus and scrollbars.</p>
              <p>Expanded Feed Suggestions with a new Marketing category and more curated sources.</p>
              <p>Fixed Reader Mode so fast article switches no longer show stale content.</p>
          </description>
      </release>

      <release version="1.10.0" date="2026-02-09">
          <description>
              <p>Fixed text scaling on HDPI screens</p>
              <p>Added Open Feed Website actions from feed lists for faster source access.</p>
              <p>Added auto-hide for articles marked as read and an option to hide feed loading errors.</p>
              <p>Improved reader mode rendering with some characters</p>
              <p>Fixed some bugs and possible crashes</p>
              <p>Improved reader mode readability with better content width and spacing on large screens.</p>
          </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.9.0" date="2026-01-20">
          <description>
              <p>Added Miniflux, Feedbin, and Bazqux sync integrations</p>
              <p>OLED theme option for true black backgrounds</p>
              <p>Mark all above/below as read feature</p>
              <p>Search filter chips for Timeline, Read, and Bookmarks</p>
              <p>Drag and drop to change feed categories</p>
              <p>Desktop splash screen</p>
              <p>Platform-appropriate keyboard shortcuts (F5 refresh, Ctrl+Shift+A mark all read)</p>
              <p>Improved reader mode rendering</p>
              <p>Better favicon retrieval</p>
              <p>Fixed various crashes and stability issues.</p>
          </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.8.0" date="2025-12-12">
          <description>
              <p>Added offline reading - articles can be automatically saved during sync</p>
              <p>Navigate between articles directly in reader mode</p>
              <p>Added cache management options to clear article content and images</p>
              <p>Improved reader mode layout and navigation</p>
              <p>Streamlined navigation drawer interface</p>
              <p>Fixed date parsing issues with some RSS feeds</p>
              <p>Improved error handling when articles fail to load</p>
              <p>Bug fixes and performance improvements</p>
          </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.7.0" date="2025-10-28">
          <description>
              <p>Added ability to open article comments directly from Reader Mode</p>
              <p>Prevents torrent files from opening in Reader Mode</p>
              <p>"Delete week-old posts" now respects current filter (Timeline, Category, Source)</p>
              <p>RSS items without links now use enclosure URLs (improves podcast feed support)</p>
              <p>Added confirmations for "mark all as read" and "delete week-old feeds" actions</p>
              <p>Fix some bugs on date handling</p>
              <p>Bug fixing and improvements</p>
          </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.6.0" date="2025-10-01">
          <description>
              <p>Added the possibility to hide articles containing specific keywords/phrases</p>
              <p>Added quick-access button in sidebar to navigate to original feed websites</p>
              <p>Fixed a bug that prevented automatic favicon fetching</p>
              <p>Added visual warnings in the drawer and feed list for feeds that fail to fetch content</p>
              <p>Added possibility to delete feed sources directly from edit screen</p>
              <p>Added "Navigate to Feed Settings" option in article context menus</p>
              <p>Added error codes for better troubleshooting</p>
              <p>The app now remembers window position and size between sessions</p>
              <p>Added tooltips to all reader mode controls</p>
              <p>Improved the dark/light mode detection</p>
              <p>Improved window theming</p>
              <p>Bug fixing and improvements</p>
          </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.5.0" date="2025-09-12">
          <description>
              <p>Fix an issue where settings weren't saved on Linux</p>
              <p>Now the text is selectable on reader mode</p>
              <p>Bug fixing and improvements</p>
          </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.4.0" date="2025-08-13">
          <description>
              <p>The identifier of the feed items changed. NOTE: There could be some duplicate items until all the feeds are updated</p>
              <p>Avoid triggering a refresh after mark all as read</p>
              <p>Add theme switcher</p>
              <p>Improve OPML importing</p>
              <p>Bug fixes and improvements</p>
              <p>Fix issue with Fresh RSS login</p>
          </description>
      </release>
    <release version="1.3.3" date="2025-08-05">
      <description>
        <p>First release!</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  
  <categories>
    <category>News</category>
  </categories>
  
  <keywords>
    <keyword>RSS reader</keyword>
    <keyword>Reader</keyword>
    <keyword>OPML</keyword>
    <keyword>rss</keyword>
  </keywords>
</component>
